谁啊
Yes? Who is it?
巴克莱太太  我是阿娜希塔·梅内德斯
Mrs. Barclay, it's Anahita Menendez.
-谁  -4D的阿娜希塔
- Who?! - Anahita from 4d.
我弄丢了手包和钥匙  能让我进去吗
I lost my purse with my keys. Would you please buzz me up?
谢谢啊  亲爱的
Well, thank you, darling.
玛莎  你觉得里克去做私家侦探是好主意吗
Martha, what do you think of Rick's P.I. venture?
做私家侦探一直是他的
Well...It's always been a big fantasy of his
美梦
to be a private investigator,
而且他说他的业务有好转
and he says that things are picking up
每天接到的来电都越来越多了
and he's getting more calls at the office every day.
是啊  都是想见他一面的粉丝
Yeah, from fans wanting to meet him
或对他失踪的两个月
or people with crazy theories
持疯狂理论的人
about where he disappeared to for two months
要么就是根本不值得一查的案子  比如失踪小猫
or cases that aren't even worth looking into, like missing cats.
这的确是屈才了
Oh, well, that does seem a bit beneath him.
要知道  他这么做是因为
You know, he did this because he was hoping
想再次跟我一起合作
that we would be able to work together again
而且以为能碰到有趣的案子
and he thought he might have some interesting cases to solve.
但现在  看上去他两样都没能如愿
But right now, it doesn't seem like he's getting much of either.
如果我了解我儿子
Well, if I know my son, then, uh...
他可能会碍于面子
he may be sticking with it
而不肯放弃  一定要坚持下去
because he's too proud to walk away.
早上好
Good morning!
哎呀  你心情不错嘛
Well, you're in a good mood.
因为我更新了
That's because I have retooled
理查德·卡塞尔侦探社网站
the Richard Castle investigations website.
现在  全世界
Now the entire world
都可以向我出色的侦探能力求助了
can have access - to my savvy detective skills.
当然  我只会接最引人瞩目的案子
Though I will take - only the most compelling cases
那种神秘而有趣的案子
rife with mystery and intrigue.
卡塞尔  网站做得真漂亮
Castle, the site looks amazing.
给我的客户当然要最好的
My clients deserve only the best.
说到客户  我这边似乎是有了
Oh, speaking of clients, looks like I've got one.
-我得走了  -我也是
- Better get going. - Me, too.
私家侦探必须按时上下班
A private investigator must keep regular office hours.
我的案子就在格林威治  你办公室附近
You know, my murder's in the village right near your office.
能送我去上班吗
You want to walk me to work?
今天会很繁忙吗
So, busy day ahead?
虽然广大群众对理查德·卡塞尔侦探社的需求
While I admit the public clamor for Richard Castle investigations
不知为何并不高涨
has been somewhat muted,
但我今早的确约了位客户
I do have a meeting with a client this morning.
希望是神秘而有趣的案子
Ah, on a case rife with mystery and intrigue, I hope.
也不是
Not exactly.
不过典型的秘密行动能让我增加经验
Thought I will gain some classic gumshoe experience.
客户要我调查女儿
The client wants me to do a background check
新男友的背景
on the daughter's new boyfriend.
16岁的男友
The boyfriend is 16.
卡塞尔  你不需要证明什么
Look, Castle, - you've got nothing to prove here
不论是对我  还是对别人
to me or to anyone else.
你真想做这个吗
Now, is this really what you want to do?
我才刚开始啊
Well, I'm just starting out.
我得稳定下来
I mean, I have to become established, right?
努力付出  你觉得呢
I got to pay my dues. What... what do you think?
我觉得如果你是真想做这个
I think that if this is what you really want to do,
那我会百分百支持你
then I'm behind you all the way.
谢谢
Thanks.
等我稳定下来
And once I do become established,
就像《妮基·希特》的小说是以你为原型
much like my Nikki Heat novels were inspired by you,
我会以自己为原型写一系列新私家侦探小说
my new series of P.I. Novels will be inspired by me.
我要做自己的缪斯
I'll be my own muse.
-说谢谢之后闭嘴就对了  -嗯  是啊
- You should have stopped at "Thanks." - Hmm. Right.
习惯了  抱歉
Old habits. Sorry.
今天工作愉快  亲爱的
Uh, have a good at work, honey. Mwah.
卡塞尔又想乱闯犯罪现场吗
Castle trying to crash the crime scene again?
没有  他自己有案子呢
No, actually, he's got a case of his own.
我们这件案子什么情况
So, what's the word on ours?
清洁工发现被害人
Oh, sanitation worker found our victim
被藏在几个垃圾袋下面
hidden under some trash bags up here.
名叫阿娜希塔·梅内德斯
She's Anahita Menendez.
阿娜希塔  阿拉伯名字
Anahita? That's an Arabic name.
她妈妈是黎巴嫩人  但她是哥伦比亚人
Yeah, her mom's Lebanese, but she's Colombian.
你怎么知道的
And you know this how?
她是有名的肥皂剧演员
She's a famous telenovela actress.
你还看肥皂剧啊
You watch telenovelas?
不不  但我姑姑看
No, no, but my tía does.
她特别喜欢阿娜希塔的剧
She's a huge fan of Anahita's show,
《绝望的圣人》
"Santos desesperados..." "Desperate saints."
她扮演一位出色的年轻精神外科医生
She plays a brilliant, young neurosurgeon...
至少我姑姑是这么说的
At least that's what my tía says.
帕穆特  跟我说说死者的情况
Hey, Perlmutter. So, tell me about our victim.
贝克特探长  见到你很高兴
Detective Beckett, so pleasant to see you.
-谢谢  -而且还没带卡塞尔来
- Thank you. - And not see Castle.
有挣扎痕迹
Uh, signs of struggle
致死原因是头部重击
and then death came by way of a blow to the head
用力很猛
delivered with such savage force,
击碎了颅顶  致她即刻死亡
it crushed the cranial vault, killing her instantly.
这是凶器
This is the murder weapon.
一段水管
It's a length of plumber's pipe.
那边垃圾桶里有好多报废的
There's a punch of scrap pieces in that trash bin over there.
犯人动手之前
Hey, our perp may have argued with her
可能跟她争执了一番
before he took that swing.
邻居说他们听到了很大的声音
Neighbors said - they overheard some loud voices
在死亡时间左右从外面传来
coming from outside right around the time of death...
是一男一女的声音
A man and a woman's.
或许杀人是一时起义
So maybe this was spontaneous...
是她认识的人  冲动杀了人
A crime of passion committed by someone she knew.
或者  杀她的是潜伏在这里的疯子水管工
Or she might have been killed by a psychotic plumber lying in wait.
这是你的卡塞尔理论吗
That your Castle theory?
-嗯  -有待改进
- Yeah. - It needs work.
穿这么漂亮不会是去看电影
Look, you don't go to the movies dressed like this,
查查她昨晚是从哪回来的
so let's find out where she came from last night.
罪犯可能跟着她一路回了家
Trouble might have followed her home.
我找到了拍摄那部电视剧的制片厂
I, uh, actually tracked down the studio where they film the telenovela.
他们或许知道
They may know.
我知道我们该找谁问了
Hey, so I figured out who we have to talk to.
他叫弗朗西斯科·埃雷拉
His name is Francisco Herrara.
他是电视台的剧集监制
He oversees the show for the network.
他...就在...
He's...Right over...
那边
There?
索菲娅·德尔·科尔多瓦  传奇般的影星
Sofia Del Cordova... a legend, a megastar.
《小娇娘》
"Chiquitas,"
《激情烈火》  《爱之途》
"El fuego de la pasión," "Caminos de amor."
-《小娇娘》  -嗯
- "Chiquitas"? - Yeah.
她的搭档  曼努埃尔·维拉洛博斯
Her costar over there, Manuel Villalobos,
他是索菲娅前夫
he and Sofia used to be married.
如今  他只是借助她的影响力
Now he just rides her coattails
靠他们的旧情
and uses his influence over her
给自己的角色加戏份
to get his role beefed up on the show.
至少我是这么听说的
At least that's what I've heard.
你确定是你姑姑是粉丝
Are you sure it's your tia who's a fan?
-是啊  -抱歉
- Yeah. - Excuse me.
作为一个刚毅并坚守原则的人
As a man of fortitude and character,
我会克制住自己不打探
I will resist the temptation to weasel in
你的案子  不过我得承认...
on your investigation, but I must confess --
我很羡慕你的案子
I have major case envy.
那你是听说了阿娜希塔·梅内德斯的事了
So you heard about Anahita Menendez?
没错  我和现场的警员聊了两句
Yeah, I talked to a uniform at the scene.
是真的吗...一个电视剧的明日之星
Is it true -- rising young telenovela star
在公寓门口被打死
struck down in her apartment?
为什么你的案子总是神秘而有趣
Why do you get all the cases rife with mystery and intrigue?
还有激情又错综复杂的男女关系
Not to mention sultry, tempestuous men and women
和夸张过头的表演
and over-the-top acting.
我觉得演得挺真的
It seems real to me.
你这就是在折磨我了
See? Now you're just torturing me.
拜托  高兴点  卡塞尔
Oh, come on. Cheer up, Castle.
你自己也有个客户的
You got a client of your own.
其实客户刚打电话过来
Actually, client just called.
女儿和男友分手了
The daughter and boyfriend broke up,
所以也不用什么背景调查了
so no more background check.
谁是头号嫌疑人  让我通过你生活吧
Who's your prime suspect? Let me live vicariously.
那个  卡塞尔  我得挂了
You know what, Castle? I have to go.
还有个目击证人等着我去问话呢
I have a witness that we have to talk to.
我也得挂了
Yeah, I got to go, too.
我另条线有一通电话进来
I got a, uh, call on the other line.
拜拜
Bye.
来吧
Come on.
我非常心痛
I'm devastated.
阿娜希塔是个好人也是个很有天赋的演员...
Anahita was an amazing person and a gifted actor --
演的神经外科医生非常传神
Very convincing as a neurosurgeon.
埃雷拉先生  你有多了解她
Mr. Herrara, how well did you know her?
非常了解
Very well.
我三年前在哥伦比亚发现了阿娜
I discovered Ana three years ago in Colombia,
从那时起我们就在一起了
and we've been together ever since.
她是个冉冉升起的新星
She was a rising star.
我们刚结束世界巡回宣传活动...
We just came off her promotional tour --
巴塞罗那  迪拜  迈阿密
Barcelona, Dubai, Miami.
她的粉丝已经遍布全世界了
She already had fans all over the world.
我们听说她昨晚出去了
We heard that she went out last night.
你知道她去哪里了吗
Do you know where?
不知道  不过索菲娅可能知道
I'm afraid I don't, but Sofia might know.
她们关系很近
They were close.
她有什么感情方面的问题吗
Did she have any relationship problems?
或是太过狂热的粉丝或者跟踪者
Issues with any overzealous fans or stalkers?
没有  不过...
No, but...
之前她的助手马库斯·塞贡多
There was a terrible incident
和她发生过不愉快
with Marcus Segundo, her assistant.
发生了什么
What happened?
阿娜因为马库斯打扰她
Ana got upset with Marcus for interrupting her
背台词而很生气
when she was memorizing her lines, and...
结果他就失控了
He lost it.
他攻击了她
He attacked her.
-打了她吗  -他想打她的
- As in hit her? - He tried to.
在场的人制止了她  阿娜也没受伤
The crew intervened, but Ana wasn't hurt.
不过情绪受到影响  这你也能想到
She was shaken up, as you can imagine.
她需要休息几天来恢复
She needed a few days off to recover.
我自然当场就解雇了马库斯
Of course, I fired Marcus on the spot,
他非常激动还威胁如果再看到阿娜
but he was furious and he threatened to kill Ana
就要杀了她
if he ever saw her again.
我们要和这家伙谈谈
All right, we need to talk to this guy.
怎么才能找到他
Where can we find him?
我办公室里有他的联系方式
I have his contact information in my office.
-我来拿给你  -我们马上回来
- I can get it for you. - We'll be back.
英年早逝  的确是惨剧
It is truly a tragedy when death strikes one so young.
曼努埃尔
Manuel,
这不是和你在第347集里对
That's the same thing you said to the parents of the child
跌落井底孩子的父母说的一样
who fell down the well in episode 347.
现在也一样表达我的真实感受
And it is as true now as it was then.
走吧
Go!
你走吧
Go.
德尔·科尔多瓦女士  我是贝克特探长
Ms. Del Cordova, I'm Detective Beckett.
真是令人心痛的消息
It's such terrible news.
我昨晚还看见阿娜的
I just saw Ana last night.
她有没有提起她要去哪里
Did she mention where she was headed?
到上西城区参加个什么活动
To the upper west side to an event of some kind.
-她跟你说的  -不是
- She told you that? - No.
她借了我的手袋所以才这么觉得的...
I just assumed because she asked to borrow my purse --
亚瑟·雷德克里夫牌的钻石扣手袋
An Arthur Radcliffe diamond-studded clutch.
她身上有吗
Was it found on her?
没有
No.
-你确定  -是的
- Are you sure? - Yes.
阿娜把它弄丢了所以才按了邻居的门铃
Ana buzzed her neighbor because she lost it.
-怎么了  -她弄丢了
- Why? - She lost it?
那个手袋是从精品店租借来的
That purse was on loan from a boutique.
明天就要还了
It's due back tomorrow.
如果不还我就要欠他们一大笔钱了
If I don't return it, I will owe them a fortune.
德尔·科尔多瓦女士  我很抱歉
Well, Ms. Del Cordova, I'm sorry.
这个我没法帮你
I can't help you.
如果我找到了  我会告诉你的
But, um, if I come across it, I'll let you know.
其实  关于那个手袋...
Actually, about that purse...
现在是早上11点
It was 11:00 in the morning.
我的电话比死掉的教堂老鼠还安静
My phone was quieter than a dead church mouse.
昨晚没命地喝了一夜酒
My head hurt after a night of hitting the sauce
现在头疼无比
like there was no tomorrow.
或许  我的命真将就此终结
And for all I knew, there was no tomorrow.
我正准备再给咖啡里加点酒
I was about to pour a smile into my coffee,
就是给我留下宿醉之痛的那种酒
have a little of the hair of the dog that bit me,
-她走了进来  -卡塞尔先生
- when she walked in. - Senor Castle?
我需要一个私家侦探
I'm looking for a private investigator.
我正准备把这个收好
I was, um, just putting this away.
我并没见过多少私家侦探
So, I haven't met many private eyes.
我也没见过多少客户...是还没有
I haven't met many clients...yet.
目前为止...今天目前为止
So far -- so far today.
你先请坐吧  怎么称呼
Um, would -- would you have a seat, Ms...?
德尔·科尔多瓦
Del Cordova.
索菲娅·德尔·科尔多瓦
Sofia Del Cordova.
是才去世的阿娜希塔·梅内德斯的
Oh, as in Sofia Del Cordova
同事  索菲娅·德尔·科尔多瓦吗
who worked with the late Anahita Menendez?
很遗憾  是的
Sadly, yes.
这也正是我来此的原因
That is why I'm here.
贝克特探长向我推荐了你
Detective Beckett recommended you.
真的吗
She did?
她说你是最棒的
She said you are the best.
她说的绝对没错  而且丝毫没有偏袒
She's absolutely right and completely unbiased.
我就知道她会想通的
I knew she'd come around.
要不我们还是直接谈正事吧
Uh, why don't we, uh, get right to business, shall we?
等我找到了一支铅笔就开始
Uh, just as soon as I find a pencil.
太好了  开始吧
Perfect timing. Okay.
先说说阿娜希塔·梅内德斯吧
Let's start with Anahita Menendez.
你对她的死有什么想说的吗
What can you tell me about her death?
她为了晚上的活动向我借了手袋
Just that she borrowed my purse for the evening,
后来她把手袋弄丢了
then she lost the purse
随后便在公寓外被杀
and was killed outside her apartment.
就你所知阿娜有什么敌人吗
And did Ana have any enemies that you knew of?
抱歉  可你为什么老问我阿娜的事
I'm sorry, but why are you asking me about Ana?
因为她是被害人
Because she's the victim.
不  我才是受害者
No, I'm the victim.
你是说情感角度讲  你失去了你的朋友
You mean emotionally speaking because you lost your friend?
-因为我的手袋不见了  -你的手袋
- Because I lost my purse. - Your purse?
贝克特探长正在调查阿娜被害的案子
Detective Beckett is investigating Ana's death,
可那个手袋到现在没找到
but the purse is still missing.
我需要找到它
I need it found.
你想让我帮你找手袋
You want me to find your purse?
那不是普通的手包  而且也不是我的
Not just any purse, and not mine.
是亚瑟·雷德克里夫的品牌提包
It's an Arthur Radcliffe original clutch
是租借给我的  明天下午五点前要还回去
on loan to me and due back tomorrow by 5:00 P.M.
这个手包价值五十万  是这个样子的
It cost $500,000 and looks just like this.
这个值五十万
It's worth half a million dollars?
你能找到它吗  卡塞尔先生
Will you find it, Mr. Castle?
我不知道还能找谁帮忙了
I don't know who else to turn to.
排查时有个目击者说
So, the canvass turned up a witness
看到阿娜被杀后一个男人逃离了现场
who saw a man fleeing the scene after Ana was killed.
这个目击者是个流浪汉
Witness is a homeless guy.
画像师正在跟他画嫌犯图像
We got him with a sketch artist right now.
这个逃走的人外貌特征什么样
And what does this fleeing man look like?
挺年轻  一米八多  一百八十多斤
Youngish, 6', 200 pounds.
跟马库斯·塞贡多一样
Just like Marcus Segundo,
那个打了阿娜的助理
the assistant who attacked Ana.
他的地铁卡显示
His metrocard shows
他昨晚从布朗克斯坐上了地铁
that he rode in from the Bronx last night
然后在阿娜家附近的站下车了
and he got off at a stop near Ana's neighborhood.
他还有蓄意伤人的前科
He also has priors for assault with intent.
阿娜为什么要雇这种人做她的助理
Why would Ana hire a guy like that to be her assistant?
弗朗西斯科·埃雷拉说
You know, Francisco Herrara said
她年轻的时候也不容易
that she had a rough upbringing, as well,
所以想给马库斯一个机会
and she wanted to give Marcus a chance.
她很信任他
She trusted him.
看来她信错人了  他现在在哪
Looks like she shouldn't have. Where is he now?
埃斯波去抓他了
Espo's bringing him in.
-你接吧  -谢谢
- I'll let you take that. - Thanks.
你好
Hello?
你给我介绍了一个案子
You referred a case to me.
-这么说你接了  -是的  当然接了
- So you took it? - Yeah, of course I did.
这样我们就能一起工作了  算是吧
That way we get to work together, sort of.
是的  我只是...  我不知道
Yeah, I just... I didn't know
找手包这种事你会不会喜欢
if you'd be excited by a lost purse.
手包
A purse?
不好意思  这可不是一般的手包
I'm sorry. This is not just some ordinary purse.
这可是个镶满钻石的提包
This is a diamond-encrusted clutch.
简直可以跟马耳他之鹰超级游艇相媲美了
It's on par with the priceless Maltese Falcon,
我会追查到底的
And I am hot on the trail.
实际上  我正准备看
Matter of fact, I'm about to pore over
阿娜昨晚可能出席了的
an exhaustive list of events
所有场合的名单
that Ana may have attended last night.
当然  除非你愿意告诉我
Unless, of course, you'd be willing to tell me
她去过哪  毕竟我们是在查同一个案子嘛
where she went, now that we're on the same team.
是啊  我也想帮你
Yeah. I wish I could help you.
明白了  所谓的"政教分离"
I get it. Church and state.
其实是我们也不知道她去过哪
That, and we don't know where she went,
所以你就只能靠自己了
So looks like you're gonna have to do
像警察那样去调查
some actual police work, you know?
去街头巷尾排查
Hit the streets. Start canvassing.
排查
Canvassing?
也就是你派埃斯波和莱恩去做的那种事
That thing you get Espo and Ryan to do.
我建议你穿一双舒适的鞋
My suggestion is you wear comfortable shoes.
卡塞尔  我得挂了
Castle, I got to go.
马库斯  你昨晚为什么要坐地铁到城里
Marcus, why'd you take the train into the city last night?
去切尔西的酒吧  什么事
To hit a bar in Chelsea. What's this about?
-你昨晚一直在那吗  -不是
- Were you there all night? - No.
喝了几瓶啤酒  大约11点半离开了
Had a few beers and left around 11:30,
溜达了一会
walked around a little.
溜达到阿娜的公寓了吗
Like to Ana's apartment?
跟阿娜有什么关系
What's Ana got to do with this?
她死了
She's dead.
什么  阿娜死了
What? Ana's dead?
被一个人用管子残忍地打死了
Murdered by someone who impulsively hit her with a pipe.
一个目击者说有一个很像你的人
A witness saw a man matching your description
离开了案发现场
leaving the crime scene.
我  不是我干的
Me? It wasn't me.
你疯了吗  我绝不会伤害阿娜的
Are you crazy? I-I would never hurt Ana.
你当着整个剧组的人打了她
You attacked her on the set in front of the entire crew.
是的  但那事是预先设计好的
Yeah, but that whole thing was staged.
这话我很难相信
That is hard to believe.
我说的是事实
No, I'm telling you it's true!
阿娜来找的我
Ana came to me.
她说她要我挑起事来
She said she needed me to start that fight with her.
她给了我三千块
She paid me $3,000
因为她知道这事会让我丢了工作
because she knew that it would cost me my job.
但是她向我保证过几周会给我找一份更好的
But she promised to give me a better one in a few weeks.
她为什么要花钱让你打她
Why would she pay you to attack her?
她说她要离开几天
She said she needed to get away for a couple of days,
但是剧组不允许她放假
but the show wouldn't give her any time off.
所以她就让我演一出戏
So she had me cause that scene.
这么说她那么做就是为了不工作
So she did all of that to skip out on work?
-为什么  -我不知道
- Why? - I don't know.
她最近神神秘秘的
She'd gotten real secretive lately.
去跟人见面
Taking meetings
而且也不告诉我是什么事
and not telling me what they were for.
她肯定有什么事
She was up to something.
可能正是这事害死了她
Maybe whatever it was is what got her killed.
马库斯的不在场证据确认了
Marcus' alibi checks out.
案发时街头的监控拍到了他在苏豪区
Street cams caught him in SOHO at the time of the murder.
他不是凶手
He's not our killer.
是的  凶手应该是...这个人
No, that would be... this guy.
根据那个流浪汉描述画的图像
Sketch came in from the homeless man.
很显然不是马库斯·塞贡多
Definitely not Marcus Segundo.
如果我们能知道阿娜昨晚去了哪
You know, if we could figure out where Ana went to last night,
或许就能知道这个人是谁了
that might tell us who this guy is.
她的信用卡显示她坐了一辆出租车
Her credit card said that she paid for a taxi.
不过我还在查出租车带她去了哪
I'm still trying to run down where it took her, though.
不好意思
Excuse me?
剧院五个小时后才开门
Auditorium doesn't open for another five hours.
我不是来听歌剧的  罗尼
I'm not here for the opera, Ronny.
我是理查德·卡塞尔  私家侦探
Richard Castle, private investigator.
能问你几个问题吗
Wonder if I could ask you a few questions.
还以为你是个作家呢
Thought you were a writer.
-怎么不干了  -没不干
- What happened? - Nothing happened.
只是在扩展业务  不关你的事...
Just expanding my brand, if that's all right with y...
你昨晚见过这个女人吗
Look, did you see this woman last night?
绝对见过
Definitely.
她昨晚来看《弄臣》的首次公演
She was here for the premiere of "Rigoletto."
你确定吗
You're sure?
是这个女人
This woman?
是的  很确定
Yeah, positive.
拜托  你觉得我能忘了她
I mean, come on. You really think I'd forget her?
她简直太性感了
She's smoking hot.
不过你知道奇怪的是什么吗
You know what the weird thing is, though?
她竟然来晚了
Is that she arrived way late.
都快演完了她才来的
Like "a few minutes before the opera ended" late.
你有没有注意她是不是拿着这个手包
Did you notice if she was carrying this purse with her?
是的  这个手包我也记得
Yeah, I remember that, too.
你能告诉她坐的位置吗
Could you direct me to where she was sitting?
她可能把手包落在那了
It could be where she left the purse.
实际上她没有去她的座位
She actually didn't go to her seat.
她直接去了洗手间
She went straight to the restroom.
有人吗
Hello?
私家侦探  正在查案
Private investigator... investigating.
这是女洗手间  卡塞尔
The ladies' room, Castle.
-没看到标志吗  -不是吧
- Did you not see the sign? - Seriously?
你知道阿娜来过这却不告诉我
You knew Ana came here and you wouldn't share?
是的  我刚知道的
Yeah, I just found out.
她是坐出租车来的
She got dropped off here by a cab.
你怎么知道的
You?
昨晚只有六个地方的活动
Well, only six events held last night
需要穿礼服  戴长手套
would require a gown and evening gloves,
这是其中之一
And the opera was one.
挺厉害
Not bad.
帕姆刚才告诉我
So, Pam here was just telling me
她昨晚看到阿娜了
that she saw Ana last night,
而且她还注意到了奇怪的事
and she witnessed something very strange.
是吗  你看到了什么奇怪的事
Really? What, uh, what was the strange thing you witnessed?
她走进来  很高兴  打了招呼
Well, she came in, very pleasant, said hi.
不是所有人都会跟我打招呼
Not everyone does that.
但然后她便走去角落
But then she went to the corner
去见另一位年轻的女士...
and met with this other young woman --
很漂亮  黑头发
pretty, dark hair.
她看起来有点像中东人
She looked middle eastern, maybe.
我看到她给了阿娜一个闪存盘
I saw her give ana a flash-drive stick.
-你是指一个优盘  -没错
- You mean like a usb drive? - Exactly.
她们互相没说一句话
They didn't say a word to each other,
然后阿娜起身  把优盘装进手包
and then Ana up and slipped that usb thing in her purse
悄悄溜走了
and snuck out like she didn't want to be seen.
那个给了阿娜优盘的女人
So, the woman that gave Ana the usb drive,
你认识她  或者有关于她的任何线索吗
did you know her or do you know anything about her?
她看起来很眼熟
She looked familiar,
很有可能是我们的季票会员
so she may be a season ticket holder.
我要一份会员名单  你的经理在吗
I need a list of those names. Is your manager in?
我去帮你叫她
I'll go find her for you.
一次在剧院里的密会
A clandestine meeting at the opera house.
一位神秘的中东女郎
A mysterious middle eastern woman
在受害人被害的几小时前
passes a flash drive to the victim
给了她一个优盘
hours before her death.
说不定我们的肥皂剧女星其实是个特工
Perhaps our telenovela actress was actually a covert operative.
很有可能  但我不知道
She may very well be, but I don't know
这对你找到她的手包有什么用
how that's gonna help you find her purse.
我肯定会找到的
And yet find it I will!
先生  麻烦你能走了吗
Sir, can you please leave now?
罗尼  你记不记得
Ronny, do you happen to remember
她离开卫生间后去了哪里
where that woman went after she left the restroom?
记得  先生
Yes, sir.
演出一结束  她就离开了
The performance ended, and she exited the building.
你看见她离开的
You saw her leave?
好吧
Ah. Right.
当时我正在前面送客人上车
See, I was out front helping patrons into their cars
我看见她朝一辆白色加长礼宾车走去
when I saw her head for a white limo.
-她上了辆豪轿  她有拿着她的手包吗  -有
- She left in a limo? Did she have the purse with her? - Yep.
知道吗  刚才那个超性感的警探也对那辆
You know what? Smoking hot detective was really interested
礼宾车很感兴趣  我之前都告诉她了
in the limo, too, and I told her all this earlier.
你之前为什么不告诉我呢
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
你又没问
You didn't ask.
有道理
That's a valid point.
好吧  那我现在问
All right, I'm -- I'm asking now.
请你告诉我关于那辆礼宾车你所记得的一切
Please tell me everything you remember about that limo.
我的客户很需要这些消息
I have a client who's counting on this.
我收到你的消息了  卡塞尔先生
I got your text, Mr. Castle.
那么
So?
阿娜在离开剧院时
Ana was picked up by a white stretch limo
是被一辆白色加长礼宾车
when she left the opera?
她去了哪里
Where did she go then?
这正是我想要找到的
Uh, well, that's what I'm trying to find out.
-这礼宾车你有印象吗  -没有
- Does that limo sound familiar to you? - No.
阿娜经常会雇佣礼宾车接送
Ana usually ordered limos through the show,
而我们只有普通的黑色林肯
and our service only has black town cars.
好吧  那你知道有谁
Okay, well, do you know anyone
会替阿娜雇一辆礼宾车
who would have ordered a limo for Ana
或者晚上提供车给她用
or maybe given her one for the evening?
她是明星
She was a celebrity.
有礼宾车接送很正常
We get limos all the time.
这车哪里来的都有可能
The limo could have come from anywhere.
但这个优盘  我很担心
But this ubs drive -- this concerns me.
为什么  里面有什么
Why? What was on it?
阿娜会搅进什么样的事
What could Ana have been mixed up in?
我不知道
I have no idea.
但如果有人是为了这个优盘而抢走手包
But if the purse was taken because someone wanted this ubs,
那我是别想找回来了
I will never get it back.
但是阿娜呼叫她邻居时
Except Ana buzzed her neighbor
特别提到了她丢了手包
and specifically told her she lost the purse,
而不是被偷的
not that it was stolen.
现在  我下一步计划是联系
Now, my next step is to contact
租车公司
the taxi - and limousine commission --
找到那辆礼宾车
locate that limo.
不论它载阿娜去了哪里
Wherever it took Ana
她的手包很有可能就丢在了那里
is probably where she lost the purse.
这辆车是你唯一的线索吗
So, this limo is your only clue?
当然不是
Of course not.
不  我有业内最好的密探
No, I have, uh, - my best operatives in the field
四处打探  收集线索
shaking the trees, generating leads.
我认为  礼宾车这条线索很有希望
And, uh, I just think that this limousine is very promising.
我可没那么乐观  卡塞尔先生
It doesn't sound so promising to me, Mr. Castle.
我们离最后期限还有一天
And we have less than a day before the deadline.
晚上打电话告诉我新的进展
Call me with an update by this evening.
好吧
Right.
礼宾车这条线索没戏
No progress on that limo
也不知道阿娜离开剧院去了哪里
or where Ana went after the opera,
但我们确定了给她优盘那个女人的身份
But we did I.D. the woman who gave her that usb drive.
莱拉·纳齐夫
Layla Nazif.
发现她在剧院有一个包厢
Tracked her down from her box seats at the opera.
她是谁
And who is she?
她是阿卜杜勒·纳齐夫的女儿
She is daughter of Abdul Nazif,
百万富翁  也是沙特有名的官员
Billionaire and high-ranking Saudi official.
他现在城里处理联合国事物
He's in town on U.N. Business.
阿娜为什么会和
So, why was Ana involved
沙特官员的女儿有联系
with the daughter of a Saudi official?
跟她有联系的不止一个人
That's not the only person she was involved with.
我调查了一下
I did some digging,
发现她那两天去了特里梅因酒店
And it turns out she went to the Tremaine Hotel
就是她请假的那两天
for the same two days - that she took off from work.
有几个工作人员看见她
Some of the staff saw her hanging out
和这个人在一起  赫曼·埃克斯
with this guy -- Herman Eckles.
那个房地产大亨
The real-estate tycoon?
她跟他有什么关系
What was she doing with him?
我给他办公室打电话  没有结果
I called his office to find out. Got stonewalled.
埃克斯的员工甚至否认他认识阿娜
Eckles' people deny he even knew ana. Huh.
和地产大亨的
A secret rendezvous
秘密约会
with a shadowy real-estate magnate,
从沙特官员的女儿莱拉·纳齐夫
a flash-drive exchange with Layla Nazif,
手里获取优盘
daughter of a Saudi official.
阿娜有一半黎巴嫩血统
Ana was half-lebanese.
也许这是场间谍活动
Perhaps this is some kind of espionage plot
-阿娜发现自己卷进了一个阴谋...  -兄弟
- and Ana found her way wrapped in a web of intrigue and -- - Bro.
你又来了
You're doing it again.
卡塞尔也想到间谍去了
Plus, Castle already pitched spies.
英雄所见略同
Oh, well, great minds.
是帕穆特  他有线索给我们
Oh, Perlmutter. He's got something for us.
我去找莱拉·纳齐夫谈谈
I'll talk to Layla Nazif.
我们去看看帕穆特有什么线索
We'll go see what Perlmutter has.
告诉你们我的发现
I'll tell you what I have --
一条可能是找出真凶的关键线索
a clue that may hold the key to who committed this murder.
那线索是
And that clue would be?
要知道  凶案并不是
You see, murders are not solved
靠古怪的假设和花哨的理论侦破的
by positing outlandish, fanciful theories --
可惜  你似乎在养成这样的习惯  莱恩警探
sad to say, a habit you seem to be acquiring, Detective Ryan.
凶案的侦破
No, crimes are solved
靠的是应用科学的方法
by applying the scientific method.
你到底打不打算告诉我们你的发现
So, are you gonna show us what you found,
还是就打算就站在这儿滔滔不绝
or you just gonna stand here and talk about it?
被害人的手腕上有淤青
There are bruises on the victim's wrist,
就像是凶手抓住了她
as if the killer seized her.
对  是挣扎的迹象  我们早就知道了
Yeah, signs of a struggle. We already know that.
但你们不知道到的是凶手留下了一枚指纹
Ah, but what you don't know is that the killer left a print.
在艰苦卓绝的检查后
After painstaking examination,
我在这里  发现了一个完整指纹
I recovered an intact print here.
在系统里搜索了吗
Did you run it through the system?
那种没技术含量的事交给笨人干吧
I leave that to lesser minds.
谢谢您抽空前来  纳齐夫小姐
Thank you for taking the time, Ms. Nazif.
您还带来了律师啊
I see you brought your lawyer.
我父亲坚持要我带的
My father insisted.
我需要问问您关于阿娜希塔·梅内德斯的事
So, I need to ask you about Anahita Menendez.
简直太可怕了
Simply awful.
我很敬佩她的
I admired her so much.
你和她是什么关系
What was your relationship?
我们认识
We were acquaintances.
我喜欢肥皂剧
You see, I adore telenovelas,
但我父亲不一样
much to the disapproval of my father.
那么激情而富有戏剧性  阿娜很有天分
The passion, the drama -- Ana had such talent.
我和她常在社交活动上见面
She and I met at social functions from time to time.
比如在剧院
Like at the opera?
剧院
The opera?
我知道了你们两个
Yeah, I gather that the two of you
-昨晚在剧院见了面  -我没有
- met at the opera last night. - I did no such thing.
但有目击者看到了你
But we have a witness that saw you.
那个目击者看错了
That witness is mistaken.
你给了阿娜一个优盘
You gave Ana a flash drive.
-上面有什么  -你的信息来源有误
- What was on it? - Your information is incorrect,
我没有义务告诉你  探长
and I am not obliged to speak with you, detective.
我有外交豁免权
I have diplomatic immunity.
见面结束了
This meeting is over.
你觉得幕后凶手是莱拉吗
So, you think Layla's behind the killing?
不知道  但她显然有所隐瞒
I don't know, but she's clearly hiding something.
莱恩  帕穆特发现的指纹查的如何了
Ryan, where are we on that print that Perlmutter found?
军方数据库发现了他的身份
We got an I.D. off the military database,
而且符合描述
and it matches our sketch.
这就是我们的凶手
This is our killer.
哈兰·马蒂斯
Harlan Mathis.
拉斯维加斯人  前海军  干过私人安保
He's out of Vegas, ex-marine, worked in private security.
但现在是单干  传闻
But now he's freelance, and word is
只要出价合适  他什么都肯干
he'll pretty much do anything if the price is right,
包括暗杀
including wet work.
谁会派马蒂斯这样的杀手杀肥皂剧明星呢
Why send a hired gun like Mathis after a telenovela star?
找到马蒂斯  问问他关于阿娜的谋杀吧
Let's find Mathis and ask him about Ana's murder.
发全境通告  通知运输安全局和国安局
Put out an APB and alert TSA and Homeland Security.
如果他还在城里  这样的人也很难找到
If he's still in town, a guy like this won't be easy to find.
但我们会尽力找
But we'll dig in.
-希望明早能有结果  -好的
- Hopefully make some headway by the morning. - Got it.
寂寞的私家侦探在熬夜办案啊
So, the lonely P.I. burning the midnight oil, huh?
谁知道找个手包这么费劲呢
Who knew finding a purse could be this exhausting?
弄清楚那辆白色豪轿带阿娜去哪了吗
So, did you figure out where the white limo took Ana?
我都查不到那是谁的车
I can't even figure out whose limo it was.
出租和豪轿委员会
The taxi and limo commissions
登记了上千辆豪轿
have thousands of limos registered,
但并不是按颜色分类的
but they're not broken down by colors,
所以我启动了B计划
so I'm working on plan "B."
好吧
Okay, well,
你打算下班了吗  今天就到这儿
You ready to get out of here, call it a night?
急什么呢  小美人
What's your rush, doll?
何不多待一会儿
Why don't you stick around a while,
歇歇脚呢
give those stems of yours a rest?
可以吗
Could I?
我独身一人
I'm all alone,
这是我第一次来陌生可怖的大城市
and this is my first time in the big, scary city.
不必闲扯  小可爱
Spare me the tall tale, precious.
像你这样的美人  总有小算盘
A dame like you? You got an angle.
对一位侦探来说  你很机智啊
You're pretty quick for a gumshoe.
来吧  讲讲你的故事
Come on. Spill the story.
时间就是金钱  而且我哪个都不多
Time is money, and I got none of either.
好吧  那我就直说好了
All right, I'll give it to you straight.
我只是个寻找私家侦探的女孩
I'm just a girl looking for a private dick --
是吗  那你的寻找已经结束了  甜心
Well, then, your search is over, sweetheart.
这里  这个好难解  好了好了
This here -- that's the tough one. There we go. I got it.
好了吗
You got it?
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle!
德尔·科尔多瓦女士
Ms. Del Cordova...
我们没想到你会来
Uh, we were not expecting you.
显然如此
Obviously.
你知道我在等什么吗
And do you know what I was expecting?
你的查案进度
An update from you.
我完全忘了
I totally forgot.
我在忙案子
I was -- I was busy working the case.
你说他是最棒的
You said he was the best.
看来这评价不是很客观吧
Maybe your rating is not so objective.
我还是先走吧
You know what? I better be on my way.
你俩显然要谈工作
You two obviously have work to discuss.
我直说了吧  卡塞尔先生
Let me be plain, Mr. Castle.
-你找到我的手包了吗  -还没  但
- Have you found my purse? - Not yet, though --
那白色豪轿带阿娜去了哪里查出来了吗
And what about where the white limousine took Ana?
我在跟进每条线索
I am following every lead.
找到线索只是时间问题
It's only a matter of time.
但是我缺的就是时间
Which is one thing I do not have.
你被解雇了  卡塞尔先生
You're fired, Mr. Castle.
什么  解雇
What? Fired?
-你不能这么做  -我已经这么做了
- You can't do that. - I just did.
那我不接受
Well, I don't accept.
你不明白解雇是什么意思吧
You do understand how firing works?
好吧
Fine.
即刻起
Effective immediately,
我雇佣我自己来查这个案子
I'm hiring myself to solve this case.
-你不能这么做  -我已经这么做了
- You can't do that. - I just did.
我一定要查清此事
I am determined to see this through.
找到你的手包就是我的使命
I've made it my mission to find your purse.
过来看看
Take a look at this.
昨晚某处  阿娜希塔的一个粉丝
Somewhere last night, one of Anahita's fans
绝对见过她在那辆豪轿里
must have seen her in that limo,
于是我在检索24小时内
so I have been going over every post,
每一条社交媒体上发布的
every tweet, every comment, every photo of Ana
有关阿娜的照片  推特和评论
that's hit social media in the last 24 hours.
她的每个粉丝网站我都设了提醒
I've set alerts on all of her fansites,
我还有个照片整理器
and I have a photo aggregator
以备有新照片发布出来
in case any new photos get posted.
事实上  这声音就是
As a matter of fact, that is the sound
新照片发布的提醒
of a fresh batch of photos arriving.
不是新的  这都是上周的了
Not so fresh. This one is from last week.
好吧
All right, well...
这个  这是昨晚的
There -- that one's from last night.
这是她带着手包离开剧院的照片
That's her leaving the opera with the purse.
这里
There.
这是阿娜从白色豪轿下车
There's Ana in the white limo.
看来她很着急啊
Looks like she's in a hurry.
她没拿着我的手包了
She doesn't have my purse.
-手包呢  -没事  等等
- Where -- where is the purse? - Okay, wait.
照片上的时间戳是11点03分
That photo's timestamped 11:03.
那是她离开剧院五分钟后的事
That's five minutes after she left the opera.
那又如何
So?
接待员说她上豪轿时
So, the usher said when she went to the limo,
是带着手包的
she had her purse with her.
如果五分钟后她离开豪轿时
If she's leaving the limo
并没有带手包的话
five minutes later without the purse...
就说明手包被她留在车里了
Then she left it inside the limousine.
只要我找到豪轿
I find that limousine,
就能找到你的手包  德尔·科尔多瓦女士
I find your purse, Ms. Del Cordova.
但没有牌照怎么找这辆车呢
But how without the license plate?
用这个
With that.
那张贴纸上有VIN码
That sticker has the VIN.
车辆识别码
The vehicle identification number
能确切地告诉我们这辆车是登记在谁名下
will tell us exactly who this car is registered to.
我知道有个人能帮我查到
And I know just the person to trace that for me.
卡塞尔先生  你真是个天才
Mr. Castle, you are a genius.
我决定再次雇你
You are hired. Again.
你睡着了吗
Are you awake?
当然没有
Oh, yeah.
好吧  我承认
Well, I admit, uh,
索菲娅闯进来撞见我们挺尴尬的
Sofia barging in on us was a little awkward.
简直丢人到家
Try mortifying.
我本该打电话告诉她新的进展
I was supposed to call her with an update.
我没想到她会亲自过来
I had no idea she'd drop by to get it in person.
对不起
I'm -- I'm so sorry.
实际上这挺搞笑的  如果你仔细想的话
It was actually kind of funny, if you think about it.
你原谅我了吗
So, I'm forgiven?
不生气到可以帮我个忙吗
Forgiven enough to ask for a favor?
也许吧
Maybe.
这要看你让我帮什么忙了
Depending on what you're asking.
你能帮我
How would you like
查一个车辆识别码吗
to trace a vin number for me?
我的天啊  卡塞尔
Oh, my god. Castle!
简直难以相信
You're unbelievable.
帮不了吗
So that's a no?
我们可能找到了凶手哈兰·马蒂斯在哪
So, we may have a location on our killer, Harlan Mathis.
怎么做到的
How'd you pull that off?
我们知道他是外地来的
Well, we knew he was from out of town,
所以我们查了汽车旅馆  酒店和短租房
so we checked motels, hotels, short-term housing.
哈莱姆区的楼管认出了他的照片
Building manager in Harlem recognized him from his photo.
他两周前用詹姆斯·海曼的名字登记入住
He checked in two weeks ago under the name James Hyndman.
走吧
All right, let's go.
纽约警局
NYPD!
安全
Clear!
没发现马蒂斯
No sign of Mathis.
我想我知道是谁雇了他
I think I may have an idea who hired him.
看这个
Check it out.
沙特领事馆的保安证件
Security credentials for the Saudi consulate.
莱拉和她父亲是沙特公民
Layla and her father are Saudi nationals.
这肯定不是巧合
That can't be a coincidence.
他们为什么要雇马蒂斯杀掉阿娜呢
Yeah, well, why would they hire Mathis to kill Ana?
我想这对你来说很激动
Well, I bet this is exciting for you.
需要机动车辆管理局帮纽约警局
Yeah, it's not every day that the DMV
侦破一桩谋杀案  可不是每天都能碰上
gets to help the NYPD crack a homicide case.
真的吗
Really?
每天
Every day.
好吧  你能帮我
Okay, well, if you just run
在你们数据库里查一下那个车辆识别码
that vin number through your database,
告诉我那辆豪轿登记在谁名下吗
tell me who the limo is registered to.
我的名字
My name?
是
It's...
莱恩
Ryan.
凯文·莱恩警探
Uh-huh. Detective Kevin Ryan.
编号42344
Badge number 42344.
你有丹布里奇集团的地址吗
And do you have an address for the Danbridge Group?
太好了
Yes!
好了
Okay.
不在这儿
It's not here.
也就是说要么是司机找到了手包  要么
Which means either the driver found the purse or --
这不是我的轿车
This isn't my limo!
把你的手机给我
Give me your phone.
你要跟我走一趟了
You and I are going for a ride.
卡塞尔先生  你在那辆车里做什么
What were you doing in the limo, Mr. Castle?
这听起来不可思议  但我在找一个手包
Uh, this is gonna sound crazy, but I was looking for a purse.
-一个手包  -是的  但它没在那
- A purse. - Yeah, and it wasn't there.
这样吧  我为闯进你的车道了歉
So why don't I just apologize for breaking into your car,
然后你让我走  算是扯平了
and you let me go, and, well, we'll just call it even?
是谁的手包
Whose purse is it?
-谁的手包  -阿娜希塔·梅内德斯
- Whose purse? - Anahita Menendez.
-关于她和我你都知道什么  -没什么
- What do you know about her and me? - Nothing.
-只知道她下车时没拿手包  -你说谎
- Just that she left the limo without her purse. - You're lying.
她上车的时候就没拿手包
She never had a purse when she got in.
谁雇了你  你到底在调查谁
Who hired you? Who are you really investigating?
-我吗  -我为什么要调查你
- Me? - Why would I investigate you?
和警察一样
For the same reason the police are.
因为阿娜·梅内德斯死了
Because Ana Menendez is dead.
你完全与之无关啊  所以
Which you clearly had nothing to do with, so -- whoa!
这  没有必要这样
Okay, see, now, that's -- that's not necessary.
我得知道你所知道的事情
I need to know what you know.
你知道我知道的一切  我什么都不知道
You do know everything I know. I know nothing.
说服我
Convince me.
哈兰·马蒂斯
Harlan Mathis!
纽约警局
NYPD!
把刀放下  立刻
Drop that knife! Now!
转过去  伸出手来
Turn around. Show me your hands.
卡塞尔
Castle?
你在这干嘛
What are you doing here?
我只是想找到阿娜的手包
I was only trying to find Ana's purse.
我怎么知道她坐过的那辆豪轿
How was I supposed to know that the limo she was in
是由她的凶手驾驶的呢
was being driven by the guy that killed her?
卡塞尔  你知不知道你有多幸运
Castle, do you realize how lucky you are?
超级幸运
Extremely lucky.
-毕竟你嫁给了我  -别岔开话题
- After all, I'm married to you. - Don't you go there.
要是我们没把哈兰·马蒂斯
What if we didn't connect Harlan Mathis
和丹布里奇集团联系起来怎么办
to the Danbridge Group?
要是那辆豪轿没有追踪系统怎么办
What if that limo didn't have lojack?
我们根本不可能找得到你
We would have no way of finding you.
要是你帮我查了那车辆识别码你就能找到
You would if you had traced that vin number for me.
这可不是你应该吸取的教训
That's not the lesson to take away here.
听着  从现在起  你得告诉我
Look, from now on, I want you to tell me
你要去哪里  你在做什么
where you're going and what you're doing.
这不公平
Uh, see, that's not fair.
那我们救了你一命
Neither is how we saved your bacon
却什么也没得到  也不公平
and got nothing to show for it.
我说  现如今
I mean, what is a rescue
救人一命值多少
from certain death worth these days?
几场尼克斯比赛的场地票吧
Floor seats to a few Knicks games.
至少也得这样
At the very least.
伙计们  救人一命
Guys, rescued from certain death?
得了吧  我可是把他捏在手心
Come on! I had him right where I wanted him!
好吧  场地票
Fine. Floor seats.
我们调查了丹布里奇集团
So, we looked into the Danbridge group.
这是阿卜杜勒·纳齐夫旗下的幌子公司
It is a front owned by a company controlled by Abdul Nazif.
那个沙特的百万富翁
The saudi billionaire?
他跟这有关吗
He's behind this?
马蒂斯是为他做事
And Mathis works for him?
我们认为在剧院是马蒂斯强迫阿娜上了车
We figure that Mathis forced Ana into the limo at the opera,
偷了那个装着优盘的手包
stole her purse with the USB in it.
说  理查德
Yes, Richard.
但马蒂斯说她上车时
But Mathis said that she didn't have the purse
没拿手包
when she got into the car.
我想我知道发生了什么
I think I know what happened.
当阿娜要离开剧院时
As Ana was leaving the opera house,
她意识到自己会被绑架
She realized she was going to be abducted.
所以在上车之前
So before she got into the limo,
她把手包丢在了剧院门口
she ditched the purse outside the opera house,
我会在那找到手包然后结案
where I will find it and solve my case!
听见没  我在告诉你我要去哪
See? I'm telling you where I'm going.
你知道我要去哪吗
You know where I'm going?
让哈兰·马蒂斯认罪
To get a confession out of Harlan Mathis.
你要去哪啊  场地票
Where you going, floor seats?
打电话
Make the call.
我没什么好说的
I have nothing to say to you.
你还没意识到自己的处境  马蒂斯先生
Then you don't grasp the situation, Mr. Mathis.
对你提出的那些指控
With all the charges you're facing
再加上阿娜希塔·梅内德斯的谋杀
plus Anahita Menendez,
等你刑满释放
by the time you get out of prison,
你已经是老年人了
you're gonna be a senior citizen.
有人雇佣你绑架她  是不是
Now, you were hired - to abduct her, weren't you?
你闭口不谈  是因为忠于雇主吗
Is this supposed to be loyalty to your employer?
因为他们可半点没为你考虑
Because they've got none towards you.
我跟阿卜杜勒·纳齐夫的人谈过了
I spoke to Abdul Nazif's people,
他们都声称从不认识你
and they claim to not know you.
所以你是孤军奋战
So you're all alone here.
-有什么好处  -地方检察官酌情减刑
- What are you offering? - Consideration from the D.A.
如果你告诉我们阿娜发生了什么事
if you tell me what happened with Ana.
有人雇我保护梅内德斯女士
I was hired to secure Ms. Menendez.
你需要做什么
What were you orders?
在歌剧院接她上车  送到纳齐夫先生那去
To pick her up at the opera and bring her to Mr. Nazif.
为什么
For what?
他想找她谈谈
He wanted to speak with her.
但她拒绝去见他
But she had refused to meet with him.
具体细节我也不知晓
I'm not clear on the specifics.
优盘是怎么回事
What about the usb?
我不知道优盘的事
I don't know about any usb.
她从剧院出来  我护送她坐进轿车里
When she left the opera, I escorted her to the limo.
过了几个信号灯之后
A few stoplights later,
她跳车逃跑了  我再没找到她
she jumped out, ran off, and I lost her.
-我不知道她后来发生了什么事  -我知道
- I don't know what happened to her after that. - I do.
你在她的公寓里抓住了她
You caught up to her at her apartment,
然后你杀了她
and then you murdered her.
这不是真的
That's not true.
有目击者看到你逃离犯罪现场
A witness saw you fleeing the crime scene.
她脖子上有你的指纹
Your print is on her neck.
我的确去过她的公寓找她
I went to her apartment to look for her,
但那时她已经死了
but she was already dead.
指纹是我在检查她脉搏的时候留下的
That print is me checking for a pulse.
你指望我会相信是别人杀了她吗
You expect me to believe that someone else killed her?
谁
Who?
我怎么会知道
How should I know?
我的任务并不是杀害她
But killing her was not my assignment.
好吧  罗尼  再确认一下
Okay, Ronny, just so we are completely clear,
你记得阿娜拿着手包离开这里
you remember seeing Ana out here with the purse?
是的  没错
Yeah, that's right.
司机护送她上了一辆白色豪轿
As the driver was escorting her into the white limo.
这么说她可能交给了别人
Okay, so it's possible she handed it off to someone,
藏进包里  像《全民公敌》里那样
stashed it in a bag, "Enemy of the State" style.
你注意到有别人接近过她吗
Did you notice anyone near her?
只有轿车司机
Uh, just the limo driver.
你最后一次见她时
All right, well, how far from the limo
豪轿离你有多远
was she when you last saw her?
她就站在那里  路边
Uh, she was like right there, just near the curb.
很好  谢谢你  罗尼
Perfect. Thank you, Ronny.
你成了我的一个昂贵习惯啊
You are getting to be an expensive habit.
好
Right.
好极了
Yes.
罗尼
Ronny!
我该给你更多小费的
I might owe you a bigger tip!
在我家乡  翻看女士的手包是很粗鲁的行为
Where I come from, it's rude to look through a lady's purse.
德尔·科尔多瓦女士
Ms. Del Cordova.
你来得真快
You got here fast.
我迫不及待要拿回那个提包
I'm very anxious to get that clutch back,
-你是知道的  -就算是假的也不在乎吗
- as you well know. - Even if it's a knockoff?
这些钻石是假的
These diamonds are fake.
这到底是怎么回事
What's really going on here?
一定是你搞错了
I'm sure you're mistaken.
请把手包和里面的东西还给我
Please give me the purse and its contents.
恐怕恕难从命
I'm afraid I can't do that.
这个优盘是谋杀调查的重要证据
This usb drive is a part of the murder investigation.
恐怕我要强迫你了  卡塞尔先生
I'm afraid I must insist, Mr. Castle.
这不是你的手包  是不是
Not your purse, is it?
也不是亚瑟·雷德克里夫的
It's not even Arthur Radcliffe's.
是阿娜的
It's Ana's.
一直以来你都是为了找这个优盘
You were after the usb drive the whole time.
为什么  里面有什么
Why? What's on it?
这不用你操心
That is not your concern.
你利用了我
You used me.
你是私家侦探
You're a private eye.
干这行不是经常遇到吗
Doesn't that come with the job?
你为了让我更拼命
You even fired me,
甚至假装解雇我
knowing I'd work that much harder
就为了找这个东西
just to find the damn thing.
看得出你跟我很像  卡塞尔先生
I could see you are like me, Mr. Castle.
你讨厌失败  但你输定了
You hate to lose, but lose you must.
交出"休盘"
The ubs, please.
是优盘
It's usb.
在我的家乡
And where I come from,
用枪指着别人是很粗鲁的行为
It's rude to point a gun at a man.
看呐
L-look at that.
她进监狱
I mean, her going to prison?
太浪费了
What a tragic waste.
真希望进监狱的是哈兰·马蒂斯
I just wish it would have been Harlan Mathis.
他为什么没进去  什么洗清了他的嫌疑
Why wasn't it? What cleared him?
豪轿的寻回系统证实
The lojack in his limo proves
阿娜被杀时  他并不在现场
that he wasn't at Ana's when she was killed.
这么说我破获了我的案子  还有你的案子
So you're saying I solved my case and your case
并且亲手擒获了凶手
and I apprehended the killer?
是啊  你击败了一个100斤的女人
Yeah, you disarmed a 110-pound woman.
一定很艰难吧
Must have been a tense moment.
尽管嘲笑我吧  不过我告诉你
You mock, but I'm telling you,
我在线学习的私家侦探自卫课程
my online P.I. Self-defense course,
就跟你的特种部队训练一样
much like your special forces training,
让我进入巅峰状态了
had me in the zone.
就好像所有事物都慢速运动
It was like everything was moving in slow-motion.
你知道那是一把道具枪吧
You do realize it was a prop gun, right?
什么
What?
没错
Yeah.
没有子弹  枪管被堵住了
No bullets, plugged barrel.
根本伤不了人
Harmless.
不过当时我并不知情
But since I didn't know that at the time,
所以我的英勇依然站得住脚
my act of valor still stands.
技术部门查看了那个优盘
Hey, so, uh, tech went over that usb drive.
原来是加密狗
Turns out it's a dongle.
什么是加密狗
What's a dongle?
就是个安全秘钥
It's basically an encrypted security key.
-可以解锁什么  -技术人员将它插入后
- That unlocks what? - When tech plugged it in, it routed them
路线指向一个位于瑞士的匿名银行账户
to an anonymous numbered bank account in Switzerland
里面有一亿美元存款
with a balance of $100 million.
一亿美元
100 million bucks?
找那个手包我应该收费更高一些的
I should have charged way more to find that purse.
德尔·科尔多瓦女士  阿娜被杀当晚
Ms. Del Cordova, where were you at 12:09
12:09分  你在哪里
the night that Ana was killed?
在家睡觉
At home in bed.
-有人可以证实吗  -没有
- And can anyone corroborate that? - No.
告诉我  为什么阿娜会持有一个可以
So, tell me, why was Ana in possession of a security key
打开存有一亿美元的瑞士银行账户的密匙呢
to a Swiss bank account containing $100 million?
我不能说
I'm not at liberty to say.
好吧  我的想法是这样的
Okay, well, here's my theory.
阿娜被卷入了
Ana was involved
莱拉·纳齐夫的一项商业交易中
in some kind of a business deal with Layla Nazif --
秘密的  非法的  或者两者皆是
Something secret, illegal, or both.
要么你对此交易知情
Now, you either knew about the deal
要么就是你也参与了这项交易
or you were involved in it, too.
尽管说  什么时候纠正我都行
Feel free to jump in - and correct me at any point.
你到阿娜那里去收钱
You went to Ana's place to collect the money.
她没有秘钥  所以你就杀了她
She didn't have the security key, so you killed her,
然后你雇佣卡塞尔找到它
and then you hired Castle to find it.
阿娜和我是生意伙伴
Ana and I were business partners,
但我没有杀她
but I did not kill her.
她是我的朋友
She was my friend.
什么生意  索菲娅
What kind of business, Sofia?
你的未来悬于一线
Your future's on the line here.
阿娜想创建史上第一个
Ana wanted to create the first
拉美女性主导的电视网
Latin-American female-driven television network.
这是她的梦想
It was her dream.
电视网
A television network?
她找我  是因为她需要一个
She came to me because she needed
懂行而有人气的人
someone with star power who knew the business,
但是我们必须保密
but we had to keep everything secret.
如果有人发现
If anyone had found out
我们打算离开《绝望的圣人》
we were trying to leave "Santos Desesperados"
那个成就我们的电视网
and the very network that created us,
那会伤到我们签协议的
it would endanger the deal.
但我们就快成功了
But the pieces were almost in place.
阿娜找到了一位投资人
Ana had found an investor that she met with --
与地产商见面  买摄影棚
a real-estate man to buy sound stages.
我想那人是赫曼·埃克斯
And I take it that was Herman Eckles
投资人是
and the investor was...
莱拉·纳齐夫
Layla Nazif?
但莱拉的父亲试图阻止她投资
But Layla's father tried to stop her from investing.
他不想自己的名号
He didn't want his name
与一个女性电视网联系在一起
associated with a woman's tv network.
所以她瞒着她父亲  把优盘给了阿娜
So she went behind his back and gave Ana the USB.
之后  阿娜就死了
The next thing I know, Ana was dead.
如果你所说属实
If what you're saying is true,
那你为何拿枪威胁卡塞尔
then why did you threaten Castle at gunpoint?
因为钱必须在今天下午五点
Because the money has to be in the escrow account
存入第三方托管账户  否则交易取消
5:00 p.m. today or the deal is off.
没时间了
Time is running out.
还有谁知道阿娜在歌剧院的会面
Who else knew about Ana's meeting at the opera house?
没了
No one.
她都没告诉我她去哪儿了
She didn't even tell me where she was going.
她只说她去上西区与莱拉会面
She just said she was meeting Layla on the upper west side.
你和阿娜在哪进行这段对话的
And where did you and ana have this conversation?
在我拖车里  那很私密
In my trailer, where it is private.
没人在附近
No one else was around.
贝克特  有线索吗
Hey, Beckett. Anything?
看来索菲娅的部分说辞是真的
Yeah, looks like part of Sofia's story holds up.
凶案发生当晚  她在家
She was at home the night of the murder.
-有人看到她了  -门卫
- Someone saw her? - Mm. The doorman.
他说她九点半进楼
He said she came in at 9:30
整晚没有离开公寓
and she didn't leave her apartment the whole night.
我们搜查了索菲娅的片场拖车
So, we searched Sofia's trailer on set.
你们绝对猜不到发现了什么
You'll never guess what we found.
警探们  有什么需要帮忙的
Detectives, what can I do for you?
你可以解释一下这个
Well, you can explain this.
这是我们录演员表演用的麦克风
It's a microphone like the ones we use to record the actors.
只不过被录音的演员
Except the actors involved
并不知道他们被录音了
didn't know - that they were being recorded.
这藏在索菲娅的拖车里
That was hidden in Sofia's trailer.
真是卑鄙
Reprehensible.
可能又是小报的人干的
It's probably the tabloids again.
相信我  我会找到这人的
Believe me, I will find the person who did this.
不会很难找
Well, you won't have to look too far.
你的调音员招供了
Your sound man caved.
他承认你上周从他那借走了这个
He admitted that you borrowed it from him last week.
你可能对阿娜和索菲娅所做之事有所怀疑
You probably suspected what Ana and Sofia were up to,
你知道她们会在拖车里谈话
and you knew that they talked in Sofia's trailer,
于是你装了窃听装置
So you bugged it.
你借此知晓阿娜打算离开
That's how you knew that Ana was planning on leaving
并带走你最红的明星
and taking - your biggest star with her.
我对此一无所知
I know nothing of this.
这是毫无根据的指控
These are outrageous accusations.
她俩才是观众观看的原因
Those two women are the reason audiences watch.
你一清二楚
You knew that.
如果阿娜的计划真的实现了
If you let Ana go forward with her plan,
电视网岂不是一无所有了
where would that leave the network?
你不也一样
Where would that leave you?
埃雷拉先生  我们拿着你的照片排查过
Mr. Herrara, we circulated your photo.
在阿娜公寓街角的咖啡馆
You were seen at the coffee shop
有人见过你
down the street from ana's apartment.
你等她回家
You waited for her to come home,
当她到了之后  你就动手了
and when she did, you snapped, didn't you?
我成就了阿娜
I made Ana.
在遇见我之前  没人知道她
Before me, she was nobody,
可她却要毁了一切
And she was going to ruin everything.
我求她别走
I begged her not to do it.
她毫不讲理
She refused to see reason.
我没想杀她
I-I never meant to kill her.
弗朗西斯科·埃雷拉  你因谋杀
Francisco Herrara, you're under arrest
阿娜希塔·梅内德斯而被捕
for the murder of Anahita Menendez.
弗朗西斯科所做之事太可怕了
It is terrible what Francisco did,
但阿娜的伟业得以保全
but Ana's legacy will live on.
我们在截止时间20分钟前
We deposited the money in escrow
把钱存入了第三方托管账户
20 minutes before the deadline.
那你还是能够创建电视网
So you'll still be able to launch the network?
交易完成
Yes, the deal is complete.
莱拉和我决定以阿娜之名联合管理公司
Layla and I agreed to co-run the company in Ana's name.
骗了你我很抱歉  卡塞尔先生
I am sorry I deceived you, Mr. Castle.
干这行经常遇到
It comes with the job.
我拿着枪指着你
And pulled a gun on you.
干这行也经常遇到
Which also comes with the job.
打扰
Excuse me.
抱歉  德尔·科尔多瓦女士  我
Um, sorry, uh, Ms. Del Cordova, I'm --
抱歉打扰  但你能
I'm sorry to bother, but do you think
在你走之前  为我姑姑签个名吗
you could sign this - for my tia before you leave?
-当然  -谢谢
- Absolutely. - Thank you.
她叫什么
What is her name?
哈维尔
Javier?
好吧  是给我签
Okay, it's -- it's -- it's for me. It's --
我一直是你的忠实粉丝
I-I've just been such a big fan of yours for so long.
你在《绝望的圣人》太赞了
You're just so great - in "Santos Desesperados"...
卡塞尔
Uh, you know what, castle?
在盖茨看到你之前  你最好先闪
We should probably get out of here before Gates sees you.
-好的  我陪你走回家  -嗯
- Right. Can I walk you home? - Yeah.
谁能知道一个丢失的手包
Who knew a missing purse
能变成一起混杂着谜团和阴谋的案子呢
would turn into a case rife with mystery and intrigue?
-谢了  -我不过是介绍了个案子
- Thanks. - Oh, all I did was refer a case.
你才是破案的人
You're the one who solved it.
有了第一个满意的客户  感觉如何
So, how does it feel to have your first satisfied customer?
想再满足一个
Like I want to satisfy another one.
这个咱可以安排
Oh, I think that can be arranged.
夕阳在赤裸城市主街上缓缓落下
As the sun set on the mean streets of the naked city,
我感到我要转运了
I could feel - my luck was about to change.
凶手被捕  案子已结
The killer was caught, my case was closed,
挽着我手臂的  是我的梦中女神
and hanging on my arm was the dame of my dreams.
你整晚都要这么旁白吗
Are you gonna be doing that all night?
如果碍到办事就不会
Not if it hurts my chances.